# NGUYEN VAN THANH TUNG

■ nguyenvanthanhtung2001@gmail.com · J +84 984924712 · 🞧 mrshaw01 · 💵 \_\_ShaW

### SUMMARY

I am an enthusiastic **Data Scientist**, driven by my strong academic foundation and passion for **Computer Science**. With 9 years of programming experience, I have actively contributed to AI research and industrial projects for 4 years, demonstrating my dedication to staying at the forefront of advancements in this field. Additionally, I have expanded my skills in developing desktop-based solutions and gained valuable experience. Continually driven by a thirst for knowledge, I am eager to apply my expertise to tackle real-world challenges. I am actively seeking opportunities to contribute to cutting-edge projects in the exciting domains of **Data Science and Artificial Intelligence**.

### **EDUCATION**

Hanoi University of Science and Technology (HUST)

Bachelor of Data Science and Artificial Intelligence; CPA: 3.80/4.00

Ostbayerische Technische Hochschule Regensburg (OTH)

Exchange Student at Department of Information Technology

Tran Phu Gifted High School

Specialized Student in Mathematics

Stanford University

Master of Computer Science - AI Specialization

Hanoi, Vietnam

August 2019 - July 2023

Regensburg, Germany

March 2021 - July 2021

Haiphong, Vietnam

August 2016 - July 2019

California, USA

December 2022 - Present

## Language

Vietnamese: Native

**English:** Proficient with a C1 TOEIC Certificate.

#### EXPERIENCE

### **Data Science Laboratory**

SOICT, HUST

 $AI\ Researcher$ 

March 2021 - July 2023

- Fields: Continual Learning (CL), Natural Language Processing (NLP), Computer Vision (CV).
- Implemented State-of-the-art (SOTA) methodologies and sought ways to improve them.

VinBigData

Hanoi, Vietnam

Teaching Assistant

July 2023 - August 2023

• Teaching assistant for Talented AI Engineer training program: Machine Learning (ML), Deep Learning (DL).

Shaw Software

Hanoi, Vietnam
May 2019 – Dec 2022

Software Developer - Self Employed

• Fields: Data Scraping, Data Management, AI Engineering, Optimization, Process Automation.

• Developed an out standing product with a monthly cash flow of 5 - 6 million \$.

## SKILL

#### Math & Basic Science

- Calculus, Algebra, Probability & Statistics
- Applied Statistics & Empirical Analysis
- Discrete Math, Optimization, General Physics

#### **Industrial Core**

- Data Structures & Algorithms
- Cryptography, Computer Networks
- Computer Architecture, Operating system
- Database, Big Data
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Machine Learning, Deep Learning
- Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing
- Business Analysis, Web Mining
- Machine Learning Operations

## Programming

- Python, Numpy, SQL, Java, C/C++, R, Django
- Design: UML, Lucid Chart
- Scraping: Network Analyzer, API, Selenium, Scrapy
- Scikit-learn, Pytorch, TensorFlow, Keras
- Data Visualization: PowerBI, Seaborn, Matplotlib
- Big Data ecosystem: Hadoop, Spark, Kafka
- Image Processing: OpenCV, Pillow, Scikit-Image
- Window, MacOS, Ubuntu experienced

## Working

- Agile Software Development, Git, AWS, Docker
- Writing: Latex
- Slide design: **Beamer**, PowerPoint
- Presentation: Vietnamese, English
- Team/independent work skills
- Efficient Googling and use of ChatGPT

### Honors & Awards

Summer 2016	Bronze Medal at Vietnam National Competition in Mathematics using Casio Calculator		
Summer 2017	Gold Medal at The competition to select excellent students		
	in the Vietnam Coastal and Red River Delta region.		
Spring 2018	Third Prize at Vietnam Olympiad in Informatics		
Winter 2018	Master Level at Codeforces		
Winter 2018	First Prize (Rank 4) at Vietnam National Free Contest Cup		
Spring 2019	First Prize (Rank 5) at Vietnam Online National Olympiad in Informatics		
Summer 2019	Odon Vallet Scholarship		
AUTUMN 2019	Top 0.07% (Rank 4/6065) at Codeforces Contest (Round 592)		
Winter 2019	Third Prize - The ICPC Asia Danang Regional Contest		
Winter 2020	Second Prize - The ICPC Asia Cantho Regional Contest		
Spring 2021	OTH (Germany) Exchange Scholarship		

#### Outstanding Projects

## Improving Rehearsal-free CRE with Within-Task Variance Awareness $\mid \mathit{CL}, \mathit{NLP} \mid$

June 2023

- Solved the Continual Relation Extraction problem.
- EMNLP 2023 Conference Submission.
- Archieved state-of-the-art (SOTA) results compared to multiple 2023 SOTA CRE baselines.

## ${\bf Automated \ Billing \ Payment \ Software} \ | \ \mathit{API}, \ \mathit{Selenium}, \ \mathit{Proxy \ Server}, \ \mathit{Parallel \ Programming}$

- Automated the payment process, minimizing manual intervention.
- Payment gateway: Tiki Ecommerce Vietnam.
- Monthly payments: 5 6 million \$.

### OTHER PROJECTS

Name	Related Fields	Time
Automated Trading in the Vietnam Stock Market	Finance	Autumn 2023
Stock Platform (SSI) Trading Package	Finance	Summer 2023
E-commerce Platform for Clothing Sales	System Design	Summer 2023
Big Data Storage for Tiki platform	Big Data, ML, DL	Spring 2023
Tiki Scraping System	Automation	Spring 2023
Continual Learning in Image Classification	DL, CL	Spring 2023
Farm RPG	Game	Summer 2022
Analysis of Vietnam High School National Exam results	Data Science	Spring 2022
Human Pose Estimation	DL, CV	Autumn 2021
Image Generation From Limited Data	DL, GAN	Summer 2021
Stock Price Prediction	ML, DL	Spring 2021
Image Classification	DL, CV	Winter 2020
Sentiment Analysis	DL, NLP	Autumn 2020
Housing Prices Prediction	ML, DL	Summer 2020
Gmail Account Manager	Automation	Summer 2020
Bitcoin Price Sideways Breaking Signal	Statistics, Probability	Spring 2020
Vehicle Routing Problem	Optimization	Spring 2020

For additional information, please check my Github (located at the top of this resume). However, please note that some industrially related projects cannot be viewed due to privacy reasons.

## Reference

Ph.D. Ngo Van Linh

Hanoi University of Science and Technology

 $Data\ Science\ Lab$ 

Prof. Khoat Than

Hanoi University of Science and Technology

 $Head\ of\ Data\ Science\ Lab$